Some people say that fairies are the stuff of fantasy.
有些人说仙子是虚幻之物
They think the world is just what you can touch and hear and see,
他们认为世界上只有你能摸到、听到、看到的东西
while others say the tales and legends cannot be dismissed.
而另一些人说并不能排除传说和神话的可能
They believe with all their hearts that fairies truly do exist.
他们笃信仙子真的存在
Through out all time, human beings and fairies never met,
从古至今 人类从来没有遇到过仙子
till one very special summer that we shall not soon forget.
直到一个非常特殊的难忘的夏天
小叮当: 夏日风暴
Life is rising up Surging forth in all directions
万物生长 纵情歌唱
Every little buttercup Is reaching out to find connections
黄花遍野
Every blade of grass Will touch the sunlight
绿草沐阳
The rain will touch the ground
雨润沃土
Growing greener than it was before
幼芽新张
Bees are droning by Spider silk is softly spinning
蜜蜂飞鸣 蜘蛛织网
Not a cloud in the sky You know it's only the beginning
万里无云 晴日方长
Every little blossom, every flower Flings its petals wide
花朵怒放
As the season comes round Once more
夏季回来
Hey, Tink! You ready for your first summer on the mainland?
嘿 叮当 这是你在这片大陆的第一个夏天 准备好了吗?
Absolutely! It's so beautiful out here.
当然 这里真美丽
I can't believe we get to stay for the whole season.
真不敢相信 我们要在这儿过整个夏天
Well, what are we waiting for? Race you down!
好呀 那还等什么? 下降了!
The breeze is blowing light and sweet The grass, a carpet at your feet
空气清新 绿草如茵
Catch the colors Feel the heat of the sun
满目缤纷 周身暖阳
All the sparrows in the dell Swirling round like a carousel
燕舞幽谷 盘旋喧嚣
Singing loud enough to tell everyone
歌向四野
Hi, guys.
嗨 伙计们
Summer's just begun
夏季来临
There it is, Tink. Fairy camp!
我们到了 叮当 仙子园
All the winters, all the springs
冬寒春暖
Lead us here on fairy wings
仙翼随风
A season of a thousand things To be done
万事待兴
Summer's just begun
夏季来临
Hiya, Cheese!
嘿 奶酪!
Summer's just begun
夏季来临
- Did you have a nice flight? - Incoming!
- 飞行还好吗? - 来了!
Keep her level! Keep her level!
保持水平 保持水平
Gear it down, Bobble!
稳住 波波!
Oh-ho!
噢...啊!
- Smashing landing, Clanky. - Thank you, Bobble
- 硬着陆 柯朗 - 谢谢 波波
Guys, I think you may have over-packed.
伙计们 我觉得你们可能超重了
- Come on, Tink. Let's go inside. - Inside?
- 来吧 叮当 我们进去 - 进去?
Tink, fairy camp isn't out here in the open.
叮当 这个外面的野地不是仙子园
We need to stay hidden from the humans.
我们要躲着人类
- We do? - Uh. Yeah.
- 非要这样吗? - 呃 是的
That's why fairy camp is in here.
所以仙子园要在这里面
Cicadas, one at a time. You, you and you. You, too.
知了们 一次一个 你 你 还有你
Wow. lt's like all of Pixie Hollow under one tree!
哇噢 这真像整个精灵谷放在了一颗树下
Blaze!
亮亮!
Hmm?
嗯
The Queen Anne's lace is looking beautiful.
安妮女王的蕾丝真好看
- How are the looms working? - Fine, thanks to you, Tink.
- 这纺织机正常吗? - 挺好的 谢谢 叮当
Next. Next. Next.
下一个 下一个 下一个
- Hows the bee-liner working? - Like a dream Tink. Thanks
- 这蜜蜂画机怎么样呀? - 和梦想的一样好 叮当 谢谢
Great. Need any help with that wagon?
那好 那辆货车要帮忙吗?
No, thanks. She's running fine.
不用 谢谢 她工作正常
Okay. Glad to hear it.
好的 那就好
Here's the first week's supply.
这是第一周的给养
Okay, I'm off. I gotta go deliver pixie dust to the other fairy camps,
好的 我出去了 我要去把仙粉分发给别的仙子园
but I'll see you in a couple days.
要几天后再见了
Oh, and Tink! Don't worry. You'll find something to fix.
噢 叮当 别担心 你会找到东西修理的
I hope so.
但愿如此
In the meantime I need to go find some lost things.
现在 我要去找一些人们的弃物了
Hold on, little miss spare parts.
等一下 小缺心眼
You're not going near the human house, are you?
你别去人类的房子附近 你会吗?
- There's a human house? - No! I mean, yes, but no.
- 那里有人类的房子? - 不! 我是说 是的 也不是
- We stay away from humans. - Oh, Iridessa!
- 我们要与人类保持距离 - 噢 伊瑞蒂瑟
- Tinker Bell knows that, don't you? - Define "stay away"
- 叮当是知道的了 对吧? - 什么叫"保持距离"
It's gonna be a long summer.
呃 这将是一个难熬的夏天
Grouchy.
生气了
- Oh, that's just Vidia being Vidia. - No, the air. It smells...
- 噢 维蒂亚就是这样 - 不 这气氛 闻起来...
...grouchy.
...可不怎么样
- We might be in for a storm. - Come on Sil.
- 暴风雨要来了 - 得了吧 秀尔
The sun is shining, the air is warm. It's a beautiful day. Nothing's gonna...
阳光明媚 暖洋洋的 是个好天 没事的...
Tinker Bell.
这个叮当
Thank goodness we're here, Father. It's just like I remember it.
谢天谢地我们到家了 爸爸 和我记得的一样
Wel, of course, my darling.
是的 当然 我亲爱的
Look at the creek and the woods and the meadow
瞧这小河、大树 还有草地
Oh! I wish it was summer all year long!
噢! 真希望全年都是夏天!
Yes, Lizzy.
是的 莉兹
Tinker Bell, what are you doing here?
叮当 你在那里做什么?
Vidia, this is amazing! It's a carriage that moves by itself!
维蒂亚 真奇妙 这是一个自己走的车!
There's no horse. Seriously, look.
真的不用马 瞧
- Do you see a horse up there? - Uh, No.
- 你看到这里有马吗? - 呃 没有
It'is a horseless carriage! And do you want to know how it works?
这是一个无马车! 你想知道他是怎么走吗?
- Not really. - So do I.
- 不怎么想 - 可是我想
I think those wheels back there move because this chain thing rotates
我觉得后面的那些轮子动 是因为这个链着的东西在转
And I think what rotates the chain is this big...
我还觉得转这个链子的是这个大...
I don't care Tinker Bell. You shouldn't be this close to the human house.
管他呢 叮当 你不应当离人类的房子这么近
What if they see us?
如果他们看到我们 会怎样?
Will you stop flitting around in there? This is serious!
你别在那里飞来飞去了 听到吗
You know what, Vidia? I think this powers the whole thing!
你知道吗 维蒂亚? 我觉得是这家伙给整个车提供动力
This, my dear, is exactly why tinkers shouldn't come to the mainland. They...
天呀 这就是为什么修理匠不应该 派到这个大陆来 他们...
Let me know if this does anything.
让我看看这是做什么的
Well, anything? Vidia, you're all wet.
好了 有什么动静吗? 维蒂亚 你都湿透了
You don't say.
你还说
Father, Father Father! Can we bring our tea and scones outside
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸! 我们可以把茶点拿到外面吗?
and have them here in the garden?
在花园里面吃?
- It would be just like a little picnic. - Not just now, Lizzy.
- 就像野餐一样 - 现在不行 莉兹
I still have to get the trunk unpacked and the house settled
我还在卸行李 拾掇房子
Father, look! What a magnificent butterfly.
爸爸 看 多么特别的一只蝴蝶
My word. Absolutely astonishing.
额的神呀 绝对怪异
It's so beautiful. What kind of butterfly is it?
它真漂亮 它是什么品种?
Well, judging from the epidermal membrane, it's cleary an apatura iris,
好的 根据外形来看 它显然是紫闪蛱蝶
but the wings have two entirely different patterns.
但这两个翅膀呈现完全不同的图案
Well, that's neary impossible.
当然 这几乎不可能
Well, I guess that's just the way the fairies decided to paint it.
好吧 我猜是仙子们决定这么画的
Hmm?
嗯?
Lizzy, faires do not paint butterfly wings
莉兹 蝴蝶翅膀不是仙子们画的
because, as you know, fairies are not real.
因为你知道的 仙子并不是真的
- Hmm! - Ugh!
- 嗯! - 呃!
But of course they are. The proof is right here.
可他们当然是真的 这就是证明
- Their paint dripped all over its wing. - Really, darling.
- 他们的颜料滴在这整个翅膀上了 - 是吗 亲爱的
Rational people consider a belief in fairies to be quite foolish.
理性的人们相信仙子是相当愚蠢的
The wings are so fresh.
这翅膀可真鲜见
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
Its chrysalis must have been in the meadow.
它的茧一定是在草地上
The meadow? Father wait!
草地? 爸爸! 等等!
That's where I'm going. Would you like to come?
我正要去那里 你也来吗?
Not now, Lizzy. I have to update my field journal.
现在不行 莉兹 我要去整理我的野外日志
My interview at the museum is tomorrow night
明天晚上我要去博物馆开会
You're going back already? We just got here.
你刚回来呀 我们才到这里
I know, sweetheart, and I'm very sorry. But I'll only be gone for the day.
我知道 乖乖 真对不起 但我只是白天到那里去
Mrs. Perkins will look after you, and I'll be back in time to tuck you in.
伯金斯太太会照顾你的 我也会按时回来送你上床睡觉
- Promise? - I promise.
- 一定? - 我肯定
- Okay. - That's a good girl.
- 那好吧 - 真是好囡囡
All clear!
安全了!
Come on, Vidia.
来呀 维蒂亚
- I can't fly. My wings are wet. - Oh! That's right. Sorry.
- 我飞不动 我的翅膀湿了 - 噢! 是呀 真抱歉
Guess you'll have to walk back.
我想你只好走回去了
But don't worry, I'll keep you company. Actually, it might be nice
不过 别担心 我会陪你的 实际上 这样可能更好
Or not So, I think I figured out the carriage.
也许不好 那我就明白这个车了
Those bottles of goop must keep it running smoothly,
这些粘湿的东西一定是用来保持平顺运行的
like snail slime, you know?
就像蜗牛的粘液 你知道吗?
Hate to see the size of the snail that stuff comes from. And at first...
那东西如果来自蜗牛 可蜗牛太小了 那么 最初...
Here's your house, little fairies. Wherever you are.
小仙子 不管你们在哪里 这是你的房子
Hmm Just needs a little something more.
嗯 还少了一点东西
But I haven't quite figured out what that sparky wire does.
但我还不知道那个闪电的线是做什么的
Hey! Maybe the whole carriage runs on lightning!
哎 也许整个车子是靠闪电运行
Are those wet wings still bugging you? Here, Vidia, let me help you.
你的湿翅膀还不能用吗? 这样 维蒂亚 我来帮你
Tinker Bell, maybe if you spent less tme causing disasters,
小叮当 也许你可以少闯点祸
you wouldn't have to help everybody so much.
这样你也用不着这么帮别人
- Hmm. The truth hurts, doesn't it? - Look! We can use these back at camp!
- 怎么这话伤着你了? - 瞧! 我们可以在仙子园用这东西
Wow. These'll be perfect for the new wagon prototype I've been working on.
哇噢 这些可用在我做的新货车原型上
Here. I bet if I took two or three and tied them together,
拿着 我打赌只要我们用两三个固定在一起
I could make one really strong wheel!
我就可以做一个真正坚固的轮子!
It's a good thing we were walking or we might never have seen these.
我们走回来可真好 要不我们就找不到这些东西了
Vidia, where are your buttons?
维蒂亚 给你的钮扣呢?
Tinker Bell, am not carrying this human junk back to camp.
小叮当 我不能把这些人类的垃圾带回仙子园
- Let's go! - Let's go!
- 快跑! - 快跑!
"欢迎仙子"
Tinker Bell, we're not supposed to go near human houses.
叮当! 我们不能靠近人类的房子
This isn't a human house.
这不是人类的房子
They're a lot bigger.
那要大得多
Besides, the sign says, "Fairies welcome."
再说 牌子上写了"欢迎仙子"
Who do you think wrote it? Humans!
你以为是谁写的? 人类!
"仙子邮箱"
Tinker Bell, you're not going in there.
叮当! 你不能进去
Please tell me you're not going in there! She went in there.
快说呀 你不会进去的 她进去了
Tinker Bell! Don't eat that! This could be a trap.
叮当! 别吃! 可能有诈
Come on, Vidia. It's perfectly safe.
得了吧 维蒂亚 这很安全
Oh, really?
噢! 真的吗?
- Oh, Vidia - Huh! Not so safe now, is it?
- 噢! 维蒂亚 - 哈! 现在不那么安全了 是吗?
Nice try, Vidia, but you re not scaring me.
干得不错 维蒂亚 但我不怕
Gosh, this thing is amazing.
天啊! 这东西真奇妙
You just don't know when to stop, do you?
你没完了 是吧?
Oh, no. Tink! Someone's coming!
噢! 不 叮当 有人过来了
The door is stuck!
这门粘住了!
Come on, Vidia You can do better than that.
得了吧 维蒂亚 能不能换个招呀
- Tink! - I wonder what this part does.
- 叮当 - 我来看看这个零件是做什么的
Tink! I'm serious! Get out of there!
叮当! 是真的 赶快出来
Just a second. Just a second.
等一下 等一下
Vidia? Vidia?
维蒂亚? 维蒂亚!
Oh Vidia, come on. Open the door. You had your little...
噢 维蒂亚 帮帮忙 把门打开 你有点...
Oh, no. What have I done?
噢! 不 我干了什么呀?
Vidia? Okay, not funny anymore.
维蒂亚? 好了 这不好玩了
A fairy!
仙子!
It's a real fairy!
是一个真的仙子哎!
Father! Father!
爸爸! 爸爸!
Father!
爸爸!
- Father! Father, Father! - Yes, Lizzy.
- 爸爸! 爸爸! 爸爸! - 我在这 莉兹
You're never going to believe what I found.
你一定不相信我看到了什么
- Maybe later, Lizzy. - But Father, Father, Father,
- 等一下 莉兹 - 可是...爸爸! 爸爸! 爸爸!
- Father Father - Just a moment, dear.
- 爸爸! 爸爸! - 等一下 亲爱的
- I'm very busy with my project. - Yes, but Father!
- 我在做事 我很忙 - 我知道 可是爸爸!
- Father! - Lizzy, please.
- 爸爸! - 莉兹 好了
I must add this extraordinary discovery to my field journal.
我一定要把这个惊人的发现加入我的野外日志
And here t is.
就是这个
Is that the butterfly we were looking at earlier?
这不是我们先前看到的那只蝴蝶吗?
Yes. Quite a specimen isn't it?
正是 很好的一个标本 不是吗?
You re not going to take it to London, are you?
你不会把它带到伦敦去吧 会吗?
Yes of course.
会的! 当然要带去
The board of trustees would never believe me
要是理事会不亲眼看到
if they didn't see it themselves.
是不会相信的
Now I'm sure to get that curatorship at the museum
现在 我能得到博物馆研究员职位了
Besides, as a member of the scientific community,
还有科学院院士
I'm obligated to share significant findings like this with my colleagues.
我也有义务与我的同事分享这非凡的发现
I know it's unfortunate for the specimen, but really, there is no otherway.
我知道对这个标本这很不幸 但我也实在没别的办法
Now, dear. What did you want me to see?
现在 亲爱的 你要让我看什么?
Uh ...
呃...
Never mind.
没什么
Where have you gone?
你跑到哪里去了?
Mr Twitches, no! Out! Out with you!
抽疯先生 不! 出去! 你出去!
Mr. Twitches!
抽疯先生!
Bad cat! No, no, no!
坏猫! 不 不 不!
Don't worry, little fairy.
别害怕 小仙子
Mr. Twitches won't bother you as long as you're in there.
你在那里面 抽疯先生就抓不到你了
Naughty cat! You're going outside.
顽皮猫! 你应该到外面去
Tnker Bell's been captured by humans!
叮当被人类抓去了
- Oh, no. - What happened? Is she okay?
- 噢 不 - 发生什么事了 她还好吗?
- Is she all right? - What's this? Tinker Bell?
- 她还好吗? - 怎么了? 叮当?
- What happened, Vidia? - Is she hurt?
- 发生什么了? 维蒂亚? - 她受伤了吗?
Tinker Bell went into this little house in the meadow and couldn't get out.
叮当进到草地上的那个小房子里 出不来了
The door got jammed.
门被卡住了
Then this human came from out of nowhere and snatched her up,
后来那个人不知从哪里冒出来 把她带走了
but I know where she is. We have to hurry and save her.
但我知道她在哪里 我们要赶快去救她
Then we better leave right away!
我们最好现在就去
Sil, do you think the storm will pass soon?
秀尔 你觉得暴雨会很快过去吗?
No, it looks like it's gonna get stronger.
不会 看起来它越下越大了
Well, there's gotta be some way to get to Tink.
好吧 一定有办法去救叮当
We can't fly in the rain and the meadow's already flooded.
我们不能在雨中飞行 而那个草地已经淹了
Maybe we don't have to fly.
可能我们不一定要飞
If we get some big leaves and sew them togetherwth stem twine...
如果我们用一些大叶子 再用草绳缝起来...
And miter-cut some twigs for the sub-flooring.
然后斜切一些树枝做甲板
Acorns as counterweights.
用橡果做压仓
Some quick-dry maple sap as reinforcement.
涂上一些速干的枫树汁来加固
What are you two talking about?
你们俩在说什么呀?
- We're gonna build a boat! - We're gonna build a boat!
- 我们要造一条船! - 我们要造一条船!
- More mushroom caps, p ease! - Here we go.
- 多搞些蘑菇帽! - 这就是了
This one goes there. That one goes there. Right?
这个放那里 那个放那里 对吗?
Righty-o, Bobble.
完全正确 波波
- Right, more reeds over here. - This thing had better work.
- 对 在这多放些芦苇 - 这东西最好管用
Give me the sap.
把树汁给我
You dip it in this way and give it a big slap like so.
你要这样泡着它 再这样拍它
Ow. Ow. Ow.
噢 噢 噢
Come on. Come on. Let's get going.
来吧 来吧 让我们来
There you go. Now you're talking!
做好了真是好办法!
It's working!
它动了!
Well, this is it.
好了 就是它了
Hey, faith...
嘿 信念...
Trust ...
信任...
- And pixie dust. - Pixie dust.
还有仙粉
Come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
Hello.
哈喽
You don't have to be scared. I'm very nice
你不用害怕 我很好的
You're so ittle.
你这么小
Your dress is very leafy. Did you make it yourself?
你的裙子真像树叶一样 是你自己做的吗?
I like your wings. They're like sparkly lace.
我喜欢你的翅膀 他们就像闪亮的蕾丝
Your hair must be so soft.
你的头发一定很软
Are you hungry? Maybe not. That's okay.
你饿吗? 可能不饿 没关系
I don't like some kinds of food, either.
我也不喜欢某些食物!
Oh!
噢!
I'm so sorry. Where are my manners?
真对不起 这真没礼貌
There you go.
出来吧
Wait! Wait! Wait! No, please! I'm not going to hurt you!
等下! 等下! 等下! 请别那样! 我没想伤害你!
Don't be afraid I just want to be your friend!
别害怕 我只想和你做朋友
I really won't hurt you. I just love fairies.
我真没想伤害你 我只是喜欢仙子
I've been drawing fairies all my life. See?
我整天画仙子 瞧
I drew that one when I was three but I did that green one last week.
这个是我三岁画的 那个绿的是上星期画的
I think it's much better.
我想这个画得好多了
I even started to paint with the watercolors Father gave me.
我画这个已经用了爸爸给我的水彩
Is it true that some fairies paint butterfly wings?
有些仙子会给蝴蝶画翅膀 是真的吗?
I knew it!
我就知道!
These are some of my favorite drawings.
这些是我最喜欢的画
This is a water fairy.
这个是水仙子
- You can tell because her skin is blue. - Blue?
- 你看她水蓝色的皮肤就知道了 - 蓝色的? !
And here is a candy fa ry living in a lollipop tree
那个是糖果仙子 住在棒棒糖树上
Do all fairies live in trees made of sweets?
仙子们都住在糖做的树上吗?
Really? What about fairy circles?
是吗? 那仙界是什么模样的?
Well, I hear that if a person steps in one,
我听说如果一个人进入仙界
a fairy has to grant them three wishes from their magic bag.
仙子会用他们的魔法袋 让他许三个愿望
But if they don't, they turn into a pile of del cious sugar,
但如果他不要 就会得到一大堆好吃的糖果
- and then younger fairies - Wait. Wait a minute.
- 等等等一下 - 然后年轻的仙子们...
...must try and turn them back into... - Where are you getting all this?
- 你从哪里知道的这些 - 会要试着把他们...
You jingle when you talk, like a little bell!
你说话时发出叮铃声 像个小铃当
So thats how fairies speak.
仙子们都这样说话吗?
So what do you think of my fairies? Oh! And my fairy house!
那么 你觉得我画的仙子怎么样? 噢! 还有我的仙子房子!
It got a little shaken up.
它被摇得有点散了
Did you make this?
是你做的吗?
I don't know what you're saying.
我听不到你说什么?
Oh. Did I make the fairy house? Yes, I did. Do you like it?
噢是我做的仙子房子吗? 是的 是我做的 你喜欢吗?
Oh. The door's stuck.
噢 门卡住了
Well, you're quite the little tinker, aren't you?
你简直就是一个小修理匠 不是吗?
What? Is that your name? Tinker?
什么? 这是你的名字? "Tinker(修理匠)"?
Er ...
呃...
Bell? Your name is Bell.
铃当? 你叫"Bell"?
Tinker? Bell?
叮当
Tinker Bell? Tinker Bell.
叮当? 叮当
What a lovely name! Well, Tinker Bell, my name's Lizzy.
好可爱的名字! 好的 叮当 我叫莉兹
Do all fairies sound the same when they talk?
所有仙子说话的时候都是这种声音吗?
How do you learn to be a fairy? Do you go to fairy school?
你怎么成为一个仙子的? 你读过仙子学校吗?
Lizzy?
莉兹?
Lizzy? Who are you talking to?
莉兹? 你在和谁说话?
My fairy!
我的仙子!
That's nice, dear. Now, I brought you something I think you'll really enjoy.
很好 亲爱的 现在我给你一些东西 我想你会喜欢的
These are some of my old field journals.
这些是我以前的野外日志
Now, I picked out the ones I thought would excite you the most.
现在 我挑出来一些 我想这会激励你的
This one on rocks and minerals is particulary interesting
这一本是关于岩石和矿石的 特别有意思
- Is there a field journal about fairies? - Of course not, Lizzy.
- 有关于仙子的野外日志吗? - 当然没有啦 莉兹
Books like this are based on fact and scientific research,
这些书都是基于事实和科学研究的
which is the quite the contrary to your little figurines and drawings.
它们和你的这些小雕像和图画完全不同
Well, just because you've never seen a fairy doesn't mean theyre not real.
可是这只说明你没见过仙子 并不表示仙子就不存在
Now, Lizzy, seeing is believing, and without proof, it's just a fairy tale.
好的 莉兹 亲眼目睹当然是可信的 但没有证明 也就只是一个仙子传说
Now, here is a blank field journal Now, you're very talented, my darling,
给 这是一本空白的野外日志 亲爱的 你是很有天赋的
and I'm sure you'll be able to fill it with your own scientific research.
我肯定你能够记录你自己的科学研究
Yes, Father.
好的 爸爸
Now if only these leaks were just pretend.
要是这些漏水也只是假象 就好了
Tinker Bell, you can come out now.
小叮当 现在你可以出来了
Look, Lizzy, thanks for showing me your collection, but I really should be...
瞧 莉兹 谢谢你让我看你的收藏 但我真的要...
You want to go?
你要走了?
Oh. I really wish you'd stay.
噢 我真希望你留下来
I'm sorry, Lizzy.
真抱歉 莉兹
Okay, I understand.
好的 我理解
So, I guess this is goodbye.
那么 我想这就是再见了
What's wrong? Can't you fly in the rain?
怎么了? 你不能在雨中飞吗?
You can stay with me until the rain stops.
在雨停之前你能留在我这里
I'll show you around my room. We can play with my toys.
我会让你参观我的房间 我们还能玩我的玩具
We'll have so much fun.
我们会很愉快的
- We're past the shallows! - Aye Drop the ma nsail!
- 我们过了浅滩了! - 放下主帆!
Dropping the mainsail!
主帆放下!
- Trim the sail! - Trimming the sail!
- 调整风帆! - 调整风帆
- Big thingy, dead ahead! Hard to port! - Hard to port! Hard to port!
- 一个大家伙 低速前进 左满舵! - 左满舵! 左满舵!
I recognize that wagon. Stay on this course!
我认得这个板车 继续向前
- Aye, Miss Vidia. Will do. - I sure hope Tink is all right.
- 是 维蒂亚 瞧好吧 - 我真希望叮当没有事
Who knows what terrible things could be happening to her right now.
谁知道她那里正在发生什么可怕的事呢
A fairy could get used to this.
仙子用上这东西多好呀
Isn't it wonderfu? Everything in this house is just your size, Tinker Bell.
这东西好吗? 这房子里的东西正好适合你的身材 叮当
That's perfume. It smells like flowers.
那是香水 闻起来像鲜花一样
Oh. My doll. She should be in bed by now.
噢 我的洋娃娃 现在他应该上床了
How old are you? I'm nine.
你多大了? 我九岁了
Do you like my dollhouse? Do fairies live in houses?
你喜欢我的木马吗? 仙子们也住在房子里吗?
What are fairies' houses made of?
仙子们的房子是用什么造的?
That's a cooker, but it doesn't actually work.
那是炊具 不过是假的
Whats your favorite food? I mean, besides sweets?
你喜欢吃么? 我是说除了糖果以外
I want to know all about real live fairies.
我想知道真实仙子们所有的事情
Perfect!
太好了!
"Scientific fairy research."
"仙子的科学研究"
Okay. What's your favorite color?
好了 你最喜欢什么颜色?
Green is my favorte color, too!
我也最喜欢绿色!
I should start from the beginning. Where do fairies come from?
我应该从头开始 仙子们是从哪里来的?
I mean, where were you born?
我是说 你在哪里出生?
Oh.
噢...
Well, that one's a lttle more complicated because...
好吧 这个问题有点复杂 因为...
So, a baby, when it laughs for the first time...
瞧 当一个孩子第一次笑的时候...
A fairy...
一个仙子...
- Uh... Uh... - Oh.
- 呃...呃... - 噢...
Right. One second.
对了 等一下
You were a funny-looking baby?
你以前是一个很开心的小孩?
A baby?
一个小孩?
Laughs?
笑了?
One?
一下?
First?
第一次?
When a baby laughs for the first time, thats when a fairy is born
当小孩第一次笑的时候 一个仙子就诞生了
Incredible.
难以想像
Lizzy, that's only the beginning.
莉兹 那才刚刚开始
Guess I always knew
正如我所知
This could all come true
终于会成真
Still it feels so new
和你在一起
Being here with you
感觉更新奇
Can't believe my eyes
不信我眼前
A new world comes ailve
新世界展现
Spring and summer Love and laughter
无论春与夏 相爱尽欢笑
We'll live happy ever after
我们常相守 快乐到永久
We'll shine brighter Than we thought we'd be
今生更闪亮 超越我想像
Because you showed me How to believe
只因你教我 如何去相信
More than just pretend
不再是虚幻
I'll make believe again
纵情去幻想
I hope this never ends
唯愿常相守
Maybe we'll be friends
我们做朋友
Now everything I know Everything I know
此景在心中
I'll never let it go Never let it go
永世都难忘
Spring and summer Love and laughter
无论春与夏 相爱尽欢笑
We'll live happy everafter
我们常相守 快乐到永久
We'll shine brighter Than we thought we'd be
今生更闪亮 超越我想像
Because you showed me How to believe
只因你教我 如何去相信
Okay, everybody, listen up.
好的 大家听我说
This road should take us straight to the human house.
这条大路会带我们一直到那个人类的房子
So how far is it from the road to the house, do you think?
那么你觉得从大路到房子有多远
Not that far, realy. The only question is, how flooded is it?
其实不远 唯一的问题是水淹了多深
That's a good point.
这是个问题
Well, I'm gonna remain optimistic.
好了 车到山前必有路
- We'll get to Tink in no time. - I'm with you, Sil.
- 我们要尽快找到叮当 - 我和你一起去 秀尔
We're almost there.
我们就快到了
Why, look, we're picking up speed already.
怎么了? 瞧 我们的速度很快了
Did you feel that? We're moving faster.
你感觉到了吗? 我们的船好快
Hey, guys! We're heading right for a waterfall!
嘿 伙计们 我们的右前方有一个瀑布!
Great polliwogs! We have to make the turn!
伟大的菜鸟们 我们要转向了
Ease the sheets and get ready to jibe!
松帆 准备换抢
What?
什么?
Ease the sheet and get ready to jibe!
松帆 准备换抢
- What? - What did he say?
- 什么? - 他说些什么呀?
Loosen the ropes and...
放掉绳子 再...
... turn the sail!
...把帆转个方向
- Oh, no! - Look out!
- 噢 不! - 小心!
Man overboard!
有人落水了!
Hard to port! Hard to port!
左满舵 左满舵!
Turn the boat! Turn the boat!
转向 转向!
Guys! We're running out of river!
伙计们 我们要冲下去了
That's all right, 'cause all we need's a little.
没事的 其实我们只需要用一点点
- Rosetta, come grab my feet. - What?
- 萝瑟塔 来拽住我的脚 - 什么?
Hang on! We're going straight down!
坚持住 我们要掉下去了
Oh, no!
噢 不!
Brace yourselves!
大家抓住
- Who's alive? - Not me
- 谁还活着? - 不是我
Me, either. I can't find a pulse! It's not there
也不是我 我摸不到脉搏了! 没有了!
I'm teling you, I don't... Oh. I'm good.
我跟你说 我没有...噢 我还好
Oh! Sorry!
噢 对不起!
Looks like were walking from here.
看来我们要步行了
- But... Walking where? - We could be anywhere.
- 可是...往哪里走 - 我们在哪里呀
Everything looks the same from down here.
从这里看哪边都是一样的
And there's no way of knowing which way to go.
怎么知道应该走哪条路
Clank! Where did you find that?
柯朗! 你在哪里找到那东西的?
I don't know. Here on the ground. Is it yours?
我不知道 它就在地上 是你的吗?
I know where we are.
我知道我们在哪里了
Tinker Bell this is so fascinating. Thank you.
叮当 这东西真迷人 谢谢!
I had no idea fairies were responsible for changing the seasons.
我以前还不知道是仙子们负责变换季节
I thought it had something to do with the Earth's axis
我还以为是地轴
as it rotated around the sun.
因为它绕着太阳转
That's what we wanted you to think.
那就是我想让你知道的
Well, I think we've covered everything. Oh. I hope Father's impressed.
好了 我想我们已经完成了 噢 我要给爸爸一个好印象
And now for the finale.
现在 最后检查一下
The whole fairy land, Pixie Hollow.
整个仙境 精灵谷
It worked! Tinker Bell, I can't wait to show Father.
它动了 叮当! 我都等不及了 去给爸爸看
Tinker Bell? Are you all right? Tinker Bell?
叮当? 你还好吗? 叮当?
Huh?
啊?
Oh Sorry. Yeah, let's go show yourdad.
噢 对不起 是呀 快去给你爸爸看
Looks like the rain has let up some.
雨好像停了
You might be able to make it home to your frends now.
现在你可以回家去找你的朋友们了
Maybe this could help you.
这个可能有用
Oh, yes.
噢! 是呀
Such a clever tinker.
真是个聪明的修理匠
Take care of yourself.
你自己保重
I'll never forget you, Tinker Bell.
我不会忘记你的 叮当
You'd best hurry. The break in the weather may not ast long.
你最好快点 雨可能不会停很久
Goodbye.
再见
And I'll never forget you, Lizzy.
我也不会忘记你的 莉兹
- Father, look - Not just now, Lizzy.
- 爸爸 瞧 - 现在不行 莉兹
My hands are rather full at the moment.
我空不出手来
I made t especially for you, Father. It's just like your field journal.
我特别为你做的 爸爸和你的野外日志一样
- It's filled with lots of facts. - Yes, yes, that sounds wonderful,
- 里面有好多事实 - 好 好 听起来很不错
but I'm in the middle of a potent al catastrophe here.
可我们这里要发大水了 我正在处理
I can't look at it now.
我现在不能看
- But Father, it's a field journal, and I... - I don't have time.
- 可是爸爸 这是一本野外日志 而且我... - 我没有时间
I have to find some way to deal with all these leaks
我得想办法对付这些漏水
before they destroy my work.
不能让它们毁了我的工作
- When will you be able to look at it? - I don't know. Maybe later.
- 那你什么时候能看呢? - 我也不知道 过一会儿吧
You always say that.
你总是这样说
Tinker Bell!
叮当!
You came back! I'm so glad to see you.
你回来了! 我真高兴再见到你
Tinker Bell, Father has no time forthe field journal.
叮当! 爸爸没有时间看这个野外日志
I think I can fix that.
我来修理他
Vidia, you sure you know where you're going?
维蒂亚 你肯定是这条路?
Yes. Tinker Bell and I walked by here.
是的 叮当和我走过这里
I just have to find the road.
我得找到那条大路
Road? What road?
大路? 什么大路?
That road!
那条大路!
That's not a road. That's a muddy river.
那不是大路 是一条泥水河
So, I guess we need to find a bridge.
我想我们得找一座桥
Or be spontaneous and jump right in.
或者正好掉在上面什么东西
It's not deep We can walk across.
不太深 我们可以趟过去
Yeah, no. I don't really do mud.
是吗 不 我真不想沾泥巴
- But you're a garden fairy! - Ironic, isn't it?
- 可你是园艺仙子呀 - 哼 你在嘲笑我 是吗?
Rosetta!
萝瑟塔!
Okay, all right. I'm coming.
好吧 好吧 我这就来了
It's squishy. Oh! What was that?
沾乎乎的 是什么东西嘛?
She's stuck!
她陷进去了!
I can get myself out of here.
我出不来了
All right, all right.
好吧 好吧
Someone just get me something to grab onto
能找一个什么东西让我抓住吗
- Got it! Clanky, rescue device. - Right, Bobble. You can count on us!
- 柯朗 去找救生设备 - 对 波波 看我们的了!
Okay. Let's give this a try.
好的 这样试试
Do you feel that? She's starting to break free.
感觉到什么了? 她开始动了
I don't think so.
我没觉得
- Come on, hurry! - Pull! Pull!
- 继续 快! - 用力拉 拉
Pull!
用力拉
用力拉!
Hello? Is somebody out there?
哈喽? 那儿有人吗?
Anyone?
有人吗?
- Grab this! Hurry! - Are you kidding me?
- 抓住这个! 快 - 你开玩笑?
Trust me. And hold on tight.
相信我 抓紧一点
Oh well.
噢! 好吧
We got the...
我们找到这个...
...rescue device. - You scared the petals right off of me!
- 救生设备 - 你吓得我的花瓣都掉了
Did we miss anything?
我们做错了什么?
"My, what a splendid tea service. I am really quite impressed.''
"多好的一个茶会呀 令人难忘"
Then I say,
然后我说
"Why, thank you, Tinker Bell.
"哎呀 谢谢你 叮当"
"You are too kind."
"你真是太好了"
You hold your pinkie out, like this,
你翘着你的小手指 就像这样
and that's the way you throw a proper tea party.
这就是你参加茶会要做的
Good night, Lizzy.
晚安 莉兹
There we... Oh!
总算...噢!
I'm going to bed.
我得去睡觉了
There just aren't enough hours in the day.
白天总是没有时间
Oh. Good morning, Tinker Bell. How did you sleep last night?
噢 早上好! 叮当 昨晚睡得好吗?
Well, I... Actually, I didn't, but that doesn't matter.
啊 我...实际上 我没睡 不过没关系
You should go downstairs to your father
你应该下楼找你爸爸了
- Lizzy? - Yes, Father?
- 莉兹 - 在这里 爸爸?
Good morning, my dear. All the leaks seem to have stopped.
早上好 亲爱的 漏水好像都停止了
I just wanted to make sure everything is okay in here.
我想确认一下这里的一切都正常
Yes. Just fine. No leaks at all. So...
是的 好了 一点儿也不漏了 那么...
Strange It's as if they mended themselves.
奇了怪了好像是它自己就好了
It's still raining outside.
外面还是在下雨
I can't imagine how on Earth such a thing could occur
不能想像 这事怎么发生的
Well, there must be an explanation that I'm just not thinking of.
好吧 肯定有什么原因 我没有想到
Well, I'm sure you'll think of it, Father.
是呀 你肯定会找出原因来的 爸爸
- Off we go. - Perhaps down in your study.
- 让我出去? - 可能就在楼下你的书房中
You always do your best thinking there. I wish you luck.
你在那里总是能好好思考 祝你好运
- Okay, well, play nicely - Yes, of course. Bye, Father.
- 好的 好吧 好好玩 - 是的 当然 再见 爸爸
Oh! That was close.
噢 门关上了
What are you doing? This s your chance
你在做什么呀? 这是你的机会呀
Is that why you fixed those leaks?
你就为这个修好了漏水?
So he can spend more time with me?
这样他就可以有更多时间陪我?
I've really been wanting to show him this
我真想让他看这个
Okay, okay. I'll go.
好的 好的 我们去吧
Father, since you have more time,
爸爸 你现在有时间了
maybe I can show you my scientific research.
我给你看看我的科学研究
- The butterfly. It's gone! - What?
- 那个蝴蝶 它跑了! - 什么?
The apatura iris with the irregular wing pattern.
那个有不规则翅膀图案的紫闪蛱蝶
I was going to present it to the museum tonight.
我还准备今天晚上在博物馆展示它呢
Oh! This was my big opportunity, and now it's gone
噢! 这对我是一个很好的机会 可它跑了
- Elizabeth, did you release it? - No.
- 伊丽莎白 是你放走了它吗? - 不是
Well, I didn't do it.
好吧 我也没做
And since there is no one else in the house,
又因为这个房间里一直没人
there is only one logical explanation.
那么只有一个合乎逻辑的解释
- It must have been you. - I didn't do it, Father.
- 一定是你 - 不是我干的 爸爸
I'm going to give you one more chance. Tell me the truth.
我再给你一次机会给我说实话
I could tell you, Father, but you wouldn't believe me.
我可以告诉你 爸爸 但你不会相信我的
Very well. Off to your room, young lady. I'm very disappointed in you.
很好 现在回你的房间去 小女士 我对你非常失望
You know, I was just thinking, if Tink were here
你知道 我刚才想到 如果叮当在这里
- how not quiet it would be right now. - You can say that again
- 肯定不会像现在这样安静 - 可不是嘛
Okay, okay, okay. Who am I?
好的 好的 好的 猜猜我是谁?
That's the exact shade!
装得还真像
Quite a bit of spirit in that little tinker, eh?
那个小修理匠还是有点灵气的 呃?
That's for sure. In fact, I still can't believe she got captured.
那是当然 实际上 我还是不相信她能被抓到
Yeah. It's very unlike Tink to be caught with her guard down.
是呀 按照叮当的机灵劲儿 不像是能被抓到的
- I wonder what really happened. - Well we'll find out soon.
- 我想知道到底发生了什么事 - 好了 很快就会知道了
Yep. With every step we take we come closer and closer to Tinker Bell
是呀 我们一步一步离叮当越来越近了
She'll te us what happened.
她会告诉我们到底发生了什么
Listen, there's something you a should know.
听着 有些事情你们应该知道了
Tinker Bell getting trapped is a my fault!
叮当被抓全是我的错
I slammed that door on Tinker Bell, to teach her a lesson
我摔那个门 想教训一下叮当
I tried to get her out, but the door was stuck.
后来我想让她出来 可是门卡住了
I tred, but I couldn't, and now I've put her and all of us in danger.
我试了 但打不开门 都是因为我 让叮当和大家都在危险中
I am so sorry.
我真的很难过
Honey, this is not your fault.
亲爱的 这不是你的错
We a know that Tink can get into plenty of trouble all by herself.
我们都知道叮当她自己很会闯祸的
It scares me to think what would have happened if you weren't there, Vidia.
维蒂亚 如果你不在旁边 还不知道会发生什么呢
I don't know what to say.
我不知道说什么好
- How about faith... - Trust...
- 来一个 信念... - 信任...
- And ... - And ...
- 还有...
And pixie dust.
还有仙粉
And pixie dust!
还有仙粉!
Can you reach it, Clanky?
你够得着吗 柯朗?
- Almost. Just a little more. - Here, let me.
- 就要够着了只差一点点 - 我来了
Okay. Now, can you see anything?
好了 现在 你能看见了吗?
No! There's a big building in the way.
不行! 被一个大建筑物挡住了
Building. It's a house. That's it! Clanky! We've got it!
建筑物 是一座房子 那就对了 柯朗 我们到了!
- What've we got? - House! Get off.
- 到什么地方了? - 房子 下来
- I'm sorry. - I can't feel my legs.
- 对不起 - 我的腿没知觉了
It doesn't matter what I say. He never believes me.
不管我说什么 他都不相信我
I'm so sorry, Lizzy.
我真抱歉 莉兹
I'm so glad you're here.
真高兴你在这里
You're my best friend.
你是我最好的朋友
I wish I were a fairy, just like you.
我真想变成一个仙子 就像你一样
Then I could help the flowers bloom and talk to animals
那样我就可以让花开放 还可以和动物说话
and fly around with the other fairies all the time.
还可以整天和别的仙子们一起飞
That would be fun.
那多么快乐呀
Where are we going?
我们去哪里?
What is going on up there?
上面在干什么呢?
I was going to present it to the museum ton ght.
我今晚要在博物馆展示
Now the butterfly is gone.
可是现在蝴蝶跑了
Oh, my! I'm... I'm flying!
噢! 天呀 我...我在飞了!
Look at me! Whee! I'm a fairy!
看我 哎 我是仙子了
All clear!
安全!
- Sorry. - Oh! Careful.
- 对不起 - 噢! 当心
- That's my ear - Sorry.
- 那是我的耳朵 - 对不起
- Sorry. - That's the nose Careful.
- 对不起 - 那是鼻子 小心
- Whoops! Sorry. - Can't see!
- 呜! 抱歉 - 我看不见了
Okay. Tinker Bell is upstairs. The little girl has her in a cage.
好的 叮当在楼上 那女孩把她装在笼子里
In a cage?
装在笼子里?
And there's also a large human in the house
这个房子里还有一个大的人类
who doesn't like creatures with wings. He pins them up in display cases.
他不喜欢长翅膀的生物 他把它们钉在展示盒里
- Great. Anything else? - Oh, yes. The cat
- 太好了 还有别的吗? - 噢 还有 那只猫
Cat! What cat?
猫! 什么猫?
- That cat! - That cat!
- 就是那个猫! - 就是那个猫!
Fawn, you're an animal fairy. What are we supposed to do?
芳纹 你是动物仙子呀 我们能怎么做?
- Fawn? - Fly!
- 芳纹? ! - 飞!
Our wings are wet.
我们的翅膀都是湿的
And who knows when they'll be dry.
谁知道什么时候才能干
Okay, okay. Run!
好的 好的 快跑!
- Clank! - Come on!
- 柯朗! - 加油!
- Clank! - I'm okay.
- 柯朗! - 我没事
We still need to get to that stairwell. Any ideas?
我们还是要到那楼梯间去 有办法吗?
If we could just build a brdge or something
也许我们架一座桥 或别的什么
- That's it. A bridge! - Guys? Guys?
- 对 一座桥! - 伙计们? 伙计们?
- A bridge made out of what? - Guys!
- 用什么造桥呢? - 伙计们!
Clank! You're a genius!
柯朗! 你真是天才!
Huh? Uh.
呃? 噢
It was nothing.
这不算什么
All right. Let's do this.
好吧 我们干吧
- We need some more plates! - Okay. Start passing them up Clanky.
- 我们还要些盘子 - 好的 柯朗把盘子递过来
Aye, aye! Here they come!
是! 这就来了!
Get ready for more. Oh, hello!
准备接着收货 呃...哈喽!
We've got a full plate back here!
盘子够了!
No, no, no. No. No, please.
不 不 不 请别过来
Get back!
回去!
Rosetta! Is this what I think it is?
萝瑟塔! 这就是我想要的东西吗?
That is exactly what you think it is. Catnip!
对了 这正是你要的 猫薄荷!
You get to Tink and we'll take care of the cat!
你去找叮当 我们来对付猫!
Got it!
明白
- Lizzy? - Coming, Father!
- 莉兹? - 请进来 爸爸!
- Lizzy? - Why, hello, Father. May I help you?
- 莉兹? - 干吗? 哈喽 爸爸有事吗?
- What's going on in here? - Nothing.
- 这里怎么了? - 没事
Nothing? Sounds like a herd of elephants have been marching up here.
没事? 声音大得像是跑过一群大象
Look at this room. It looks like a cyclone hit it.
瞧瞧这房间 像是刮过龙卷风了
- It's not that bad. - Not that bad?
- 还没那么糟 - 没那么糟?
Your books are a overthe floor, your toys are everywhere
你的书都跑到地板上去了 玩具到处都是
and you tore your curtains What?
你还把窗帘扯下来了 怎么了?
How did you get footprints on the ceiling?
你怎么把脚印搞到天花板上去的?
This is simply too much.
这简直太过分了
A temper tantrum of this magnitude is unacceptable.
你不可以这样胡闹
But I wasn't having a tantrum!
可我没有在胡闹
Then how did this happen? And the truth this time.
那么这是怎么回事? 这次你要说真话
If I tell you the truth you still won't believe me.
我和你说真话 但你还是不会相信我
Elizabeth, the truth.
伊丽莎白! 说真话
I was flying. My fairy showed me how.
我在飞 我的仙子教我的
Oh, forgoodness sake. Your make-believe fairy did this?
噢 你饶了我吧 又是你的那些虚构的仙子干的?
You've got to stop this nonsense!
你别再这么不着调了!
But it's not nonsense, Father. It's the truth!
我没有不着调 爸爸 这是真的!
You have a real fairy living in your room?
在你的房间有一个真的仙子?
Yes! And I can prove it.
是的 我可以证明
Just look at the research we did.
你看看我做的研究
Elizabeth. This is what you've been doing?
伊丽莎白 这就是你做的?
Field journals are to be filled with fact, not fairy tales.
日志是用来记录事实的 而不是仙子传说
But Father, these are facts!
可是 爸爸 这些是事实!
I don't understand this foolishness, Lizzy. You have such talent
我不能理解这些愚蠢的东西 莉兹 这就是你的天赋?
- Why would you waste it this way? - Why can't you just believe me?
- 你为什么要这么糟蹋它? - 你为什么就不能相信我呢?
I believe in what is real,
我相信那些真实的东西
and it's about time you started doing the same.
而你这些年以来 都在做这些
Father, wait!
爸爸 等等!
I know this is difficult for you to understand
我知道你很难理解
but this is all make-believe.
但这些都是虚构的
- No! They're real! - Elizabeth, this discuss on is over.
- 不是的! 他们是真的! - 伊丽莎白 讨论到此结束
But Father!
可是 爸爸!
It ... It.
这...这...
See? I told you. Faires are real!
瞧? 我告诉你了 仙子是真实的!
It's okay. She won't hurt you.
好了 她不会伤害你的
It's... Well, it's extraordinary!
这... 好吧 这东西可真特别!
Aren't her wings beautiful?
她的翅膀真漂亮 是吧?
Yes. Very similarto Apoidea. Or, no, no, odonata.
是的 和膜翅目蜂总科的翅膀很类似 或者 不 不 是蜻蜓目的
Look at the limb proportionality to the cranial radius.
瞧 翅膀以头部为中心对称
- Fascinating! - Isn't she magical?
- 真令人着迷 - 她是不是不可思议?
She's some sort of evolutionary mutation
她应该是某种进化的变种
She's not a bug, she's a person.
她不是虫子 她是人
- Exactly! - Tinker Bell
- 正确! - 叮当
This is going to be the discovery of the century!
这将会是世纪的发现!
Tink, watch out!
叮当 小心!
- Vidia? - Get out of the way!
- 维蒂亚? - 赶紧走开!
I must get this to the museum right away!
我现在要把这个带到博物馆去!
Father, no!
爸爸 不!
Please, Father! Wait!
求求你 爸爸 等一下!
- You can't do this - Lizzy, I don't have much time.
- 你不能这样做 - 莉兹 我没有时间了
The trustees will only wait for me until 9:00
理事会只等我到9:00
Please, go back in the house.
帮帮忙 回房子里去
Don't worry. Mrs. Perkins wil be here any second.
别担心 帕金斯太太随时都在的
Tinker Bell, I'm so sorry!
叮当! 真对不起!
My father's taking your friend to the city!
爸爸把你的朋友带到城里去了!
Step, step step.
走 走 走
- Tinker Bell? - Tinker Bell!
- 小叮当? - 小叮当!
Look, it's your frends.
瞧 是你的朋友们
- Hurry - That's it. Good kitty.
- 快 - 这就对了 好猫咪
Look, Lizzy's father trapped Vidia in a jar while she was saving me.
瞧 莉兹的爸爸把维蒂亚扣在广口瓶里了 当时她救了我
- We have to hurry and rescue her. - Here we go again!
- 我们要赶快去救她 - 我们又要出发了
- How are we gonna get there? - Yeah, it's still raining.
- 可我们怎么去呀? - 是呀 还在下雨呀
Maybe we can't fly in the rain but I think I know someone who can.
我们不能冒雨飞行 但我想有人可以
I'm scared. Tinker Bell.
叮当 我有点害怕
Floating around my room is one thing, but flying all the way to London
在房间里漂浮是一回事 可伦敦太远了...
That easy. huh?
很容易的 哈?
Okay. I'll be brave.
好吧 我会勇敢的
All right, fairies. We need all the pixie dust we can get.
好了 仙子们 使出所有的仙粉
This girl's got a long journey ahead of her.
这个小姑娘要飞很远的路程
All aboard!
全体登机!
Ready?
准备好了吗?
This better work.
干得不错
Oh! Sorry, fairies.
噢对不起 仙子们
Careful now!
小心了!
Hi, Mrs. Perkins. Bye, Mrs. Perkins.
哎! 帕金斯太太再见 帕金斯太太
Bye, dear. Fly back soon.
再见 亲爱的 早点飞回来呀
Oh! Good idea.
噢 好主意
Sorry!
对不起!
Out of the way!
把路让开!
There he is!
他在那儿!
Tinker Bell, I can't keep up. He's going too fast.
叮当 我跟不上 他太快了
Tink! Tinker Bell, no!
小叮当? 叮当 别!
No, no, no, no, no, no! Come on!
不 不 不 不! 别这样!
Come on, please, let them still be there.
赶快 但愿他们还在等我
- Father - What in the world?
- 爸爸 - 什么声音?
Father, stop!
爸爸 停下!
Don't take her in there!
别把她带进去!
It... It... It... It can't be.
这...这...这不可能呀
Lizzy? You re flying.
莉兹? 你在飞?
Yes, I am.
是呀 我在飞
But how? How are you doing that?
可是怎么? 你怎么飞起来的?
My friends showed me how.
我的朋友们教我的
I... I don't understand.
我...我想不通
You don't have to understand.
你不必想通
You just have to believe.
你只要相信就好了
I do believe.
我相信
I do believe!
Oh! Father!
噢! 爸爸!
Lizzy, I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
莉兹 对不起 对不起
I'll never doubt you again.
我不会再怀疑你了
Vidia!
维蒂亚!
- Let's go home, Father. - But how?
- 我们回家吧 爸爸 - 可怎么回去呢?
Think happy thoughts.
想点快乐的事
- Lift your arms and kick yourfeet! - Careful!
- 抬起你的双手 然后踢腿! - 小心!
I think I'm gettng the hang of it. Yes! Why, I'm flying!
我想我会了 是的! 真棒 我在飞!
- You're doing it, Father! You're doing it! - I could get used to this! Just a second.
- 你是在飞 爸爸! 你是在飞! - 我应该已经习惯了 等一下
There's something I've always wanted to do. Follow me!
有件事我一直想做的 跟我来!
- Hey Tink. - Hey, Vidia.
- 嘿! 叮当 - 嘿 维蒂亚
So, you ever been to one of these before?
你以前参加过这个吗?
Yeah. It's pretty fun.
是呀很好玩的
- What are you supposed to do? - It's easy. You just pick this up.
- 那应该怎么做? - 这容易 你只要把这个拿起来
- Like this? - Yeah. And then you hold it out.
- 像这样? - 对 再伸出去
- Got it - Now, just raise your pinkie, like this.
- 我会了 - 现在 把你的小指头翘起来 像这样
And then you say, "Excuse me, miss, but may I have a spot of tea?
然后你说 "对不起 小姐 我可以再要一点茶吗? "
Why, certainly, Miss Bell. A nice, fresh cup.
当然 叮当小姐 刚泡的好茶
Oh. But of course you may have one, too.
噢 当然 你也可以来一杯
This is a tea party after all.
这就是所谓的茶会
How about a cup for me, Miss Griffiths?
能给我一杯吗? 格里菲斯女士
Why, of course, Doctor.
当然可以 博士
- It's my pleasure, I'm sure. - Thank you.
- 我想这是我的荣幸 - 谢谢
- And would you ike one lump or two? - Make mine three.
- 你要一块还是两块糖? - 给我三块
Oh. father!
噢! 爸爸!
Thank you.
谢谢
- Isn't this pleasant, Father? - I can't imagine anything better.
- 这样真好 是吧? 爸爸 - 我觉得好得不能再好了
Although, chiming the Big Ben comes a close second.
就是大本钟又响了 时间过得真快
- Oh, my goodness. - Scrumptious.
- 噢 真过瘾 - 味美之极
Don't even think about it.
想都不要去想
So, where were we? Ah, yes.
那 我们说到哪里了? 哦 这儿
"Fairies have many magica talents. They can ta k to an mals,
"仙子们有很多奇妙的能力 他们和动物交谈 "
make the flowers bloom, create warm summer breezes."
"让花儿开放 吹夏日清风"
Oh. Lizzy, what a beautiful drawing.
噢! 莉兹 这幅画真好看
"And some invent the most clever little gadgets."
"还有一些仙子专门发明顶级聪明的工具"
Well, Tink you found something to fix after all.
叮当 后来你找到要修理的东西了吗
Yeah. I guess I did.
是的 我想我找到了
"They bring the change of seasons, and help nature in many ways.
"他们变换季节 还在很多方面帮助大自然"
"But the best talent a fairy can have is simply being a friend. '
"但是 仙子们最好的能力 就是成为朋友"
The breezes blow the clouds away
清风和煦乌云散
A million things I want to say
千言万语在心间
I don't ever want this day To be done
唯愿今日成永远
Summer's just begun
夏季来临
Never seen the sky so blue
碧空如洗
Everything is clear and new
万物新
Happy just to be with you in the sun
我心愉悦因有你
Summer's just begun
夏季来临
[插曲:《如何去相信》]
Hold my hand and fly
携手共飞翔
Never say goodbye
我们不分开
Cross the open sky
穿行碧空里
Leave the world behind
尘世尽抛开
I will be all right
有你在身边
If you stay by my side
烦忧不再来
Spring and summer Love and laughter
无论春与夏 相爱尽欢笑
We'll live happy ever after
我们常相守 快乐到永久
We'll fly higher Than we thought we'd be
比翼齐高飞 超越我想像
Because you showed me
只因你教我
How to belleve
如何去相信
Tiny shining star
闪亮如明星
I know who you are
我知你是谁
You're never very far
你并不遥远
We'll never be apart
我们在一起
Sparkle in my eye
闪烁我眼中
Light the sky tonight
光辉耀夜空
Spring and summer Love and laughter
无论春与夏 相爱尽欢笑
We'll live happy ever after
我们常相守 快乐到永久
We'll fly higher Than we thought we'd be
比翼齐高飞 超越我想像
Because you showed me
只因你教我
How to belleve
如何去相信...
In me
我自己
Fall and winter Love and laughter
无论秋与冬 相爱尽欢笑
We'll live happy ever after
我们常相守 快乐到永久
We'll fly higher Than we thought we'd be
比翼齐高飞 超越我想像
Because you showed me
只因你教我
How to belleve
如何去相信
Yeah
耶...
Hold my hand and fly
携手共飞翔
Never say goodbye
我们不分开